# **BRYAN SCHONHAUT**

4201 Cathedral Ave NW Apt 821E, Washington 20016 H: 845-544-3439 ♦ bs7792a@student.american.edu

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated college student with crisis intervention training and excellent interpersonal skills. Adept at multiple types of editing and writing software, including but not limited to, Excel, PowerPoint, and Word. Familiar with conducting strong, independent and professional research.

## SKILLS

- Crisis intervention techniques
- Interpersonal skills

- Intermediate level Spanish
- Proficient in MS Word, Excel and PowerPoint

## WORK HISTORY

**OHL Staffer**, 09/2015 to 12/2015

**RAINN** – Washington

- Provided support and emergency resources to visitors.
- Underwent a 40 hour training program encompassing sexual assault, domestic violence, crisis intervention and online communication.
- Initiated crisis intervention by following official crisis communication plans and training.

Clerk/Cashier, 07/2016 to Current

CVS - Monroe, NY

- Provided excellent customer service and support to customers.
- Maintained a clean, organized work environment.

Ski Instructor, 12/2013 to 04/2015

Mount Peter Ski Area – Warwick, NY

- Assessed skill levels and provided appropriate instruction to individuals and groups (2-14 people), 3-4 days a week.
- Researched skiing articles to assist students in improving their technique and form.
- Trained new employees and helped manage customers.

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts**: Justice and Law, Current **American University** - Washington, D.C.

High School Diploma: June 2015

Warwick Valley High School - Warwick, NY

#### INTERESTS

Phi Sigma Pi National Honor Fraternity Washington, D.C. Member September 2016 - Present

- Member of the Fundraising Committee
- Volunteered for charitable fundraisers and events

Warwick Valley Soccer Club Warwick, NY Coach, Assistant Coach Fall 2014 - spring 2015

- Instructed boys ages 12-13 in soccer and devised practices that would improve their skills
- Scheduled practices with parents of team members in an appropriate and timely manner

Science Research Warwick, NY Member September 2012 - June 2014

• Learned proper presentation and speech techniques Independently sought out mentor in preferred scientific field of study

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS